Barney要是认为这样能行 他准是疯了
Barney is crazy if he\nthinks this is gonna work.
我认为这能行
I think it's gonna work.
我希望不行
I hope it doesn't work.
他来了
Here he comes.
- 这位 你叫什么名字?\n- 什么?
- You there, what's your name?\n- Excuse me?
你的名字 女士 你叫什么名字?
Your name, woman, what's your name?
Cindy\nCindy.
我就知道
I knew it.
你是那位Cindy 能改变一切 \n或是给我们带来不可避免的灾难的人
You're the Cindy, the one who can change\neverything, or spell our inevitable doom.
听我说 Cindy
Now listen to me, Cindy.
我是Barney Stinson \n我来自未来 有紧急任务在身
I am Barney Stinson, and I am on\nan urgent mission from the future.
未来?
The future?
未来 我能证明
The future, and I can prove it to you.
4秒后 那桌的女士会给那男的一巴掌
In exactly four seconds, the woman at\nthat booth is going to slap that man.
你干啥?
What the hell?
在几分钟后 年轻的我\n将会从那扇门进来到你们的时空
In a few minutes, the young me from your\ntime is going to come through that door.
Cindy 我知道这听起来很疯狂\n但为了拯救地球
Now, Cindy, I know this sounds insane,\nbut in order to save the planet,
你今晚要和他上床
you need to sleep with him tonight.
什么? 我...
What? I...
今晚和Barney Stinson上床\n以他希望的任何方式
Sleep with Barney Stinson tonight,\nin whatever way he wants it,
不然他就无法解决全球变暖问题\n也就拯救不了人类
or he won't be able to find the solution\nto global warming that saves the human race.
你说啥呢?
What are you talking about?
我没时间解释了
I have no time to explain.
我得在时空漩涡关闭之前回到时间机器里
I have to get back to the reality\naccelerator before the vortex closes.
只有你能拯救我们 Cindy
Only you can save us, Cindy.
我走了!
I must away!
好吧 伙计们 还有14小时搬家工就来了
Okay, guys, the movers\nare coming in 14 hours.
我们得回楼上打包好
We gotta get back upstairs\nand finish packing.
你们还没打包完呢?
You guys still aren't finished packing?
怎么能用这么长时间?
How is this taking so long?
嘿 所有我们20多岁的美好回忆\n都发生在那公寓里
Hey, all the great memories of our\n20s took place in that apartment.
可不是把东西扔进箱子那样
It's not like throwing stuff in a box.
你会缅怀的
You start to reminisce.
我不是 关键就是?
Not me. The key?
扔出东西 永不回头
Throw stuff out and never look back.
我要去日本了 我才花半小时去收拾
I'm moving to Japan. It\ntook me a half hour to pack.
半小时?
A half hour?
要不是一个朋友哭哭啼啼的打电话给我\n20分钟就搞定了
Well, it would have taken me 20\nminutes, but a friend called me in tears.
搬家真伤感
Moving is really emotional, okay?
当然 我是说 一切在变
It is. I mean, everything is changing.
我将要和Stella住在新泽西\n你们会住在你们的新家
I'm gonna be living in New Jersey with\nStella, you guys will be in your new place.
你要在东京开始新的工作
You're starting a new job in Tokyo.
一个时代的结束
It's the end of an era.
我想我们要干一杯 但不是平常那样
I think we should have a\ntoast, but not our usual crap.
嘿 Wendy 来瓶这里最贵的威士忌
Hey, uh, Wendy, your most\nexpensive bottle of scotch.
50年陈酿的Glen McKenna 2500美元
That's 50-year-old Glen\nMcKenna, and it's $2,500.
很好
Excellent.
一瓶那个 再来点啤酒小吃 你们说呢\n不要威士忌了?
A bottle of that with beer chasers, and\nwhat do you think, cancel the scotch?
嗯...
Yeah.
加冰的伏特加
Vodka rocks.
肯定没戏
It's not gonna work.
哦 天啊 你是...哦 天啊!
Oh, my God, you're... Oh, my God!
能请你喝杯酒吗?
Can I buy you a drink?
我想1小时里我能先喝点酒\n剩下的45分钟还能干点别的
I suppose I have time for one drink and 45\nminutes to an hour of some other activity,
但那之后 我要接着去进行绝密的研究
but after that, I have to get back to a\ntop-secret research project I'm working on.
全球变暖?
Global warming?
妈呀 你咋知道的?
My God, how did you know that?
老爸老妈浪漫史\n第四季 第4集
How I Met Your\nMother Season04 Episode04
嘿 看这个
Hey, look at this.
我们第一天搬进来时的照片
A photo from the first day\nwe moved into this place.
这么多美好的回忆
So many great memories.
看到没? 那才是你要扔掉的垃圾
See? That is exactly the type\nof crap you should be trashing.
你都不保留照片的吗?
So you don't keep any photos?
不 那就像情书 年鉴或是骨灰
No, they're like love letters\nor yearbooks or someone's ashes.
留着占地方
They just take up space.
再说了 Stella绝不会让你\n留半点这些垃圾的
Besides, Stella's not gonna\nlet you keep half of this junk.
他为什么不让?
Why wouldn't she?
哦 Ted 哦 小可爱
Oh, Ted, oh, sweetie.
男人要知道 当你和女人一起住的时候
Okay, here's the thing that guys only\nlearn after they move in with a woman.
你所有的东西都很白痴
All of your stuff is stupid.
像是什么?
Like what?
像是你在文艺复兴节集会上买的东西
Um, like anything you bought\nat a Renaissance Faire.
喝完世界上所有的蜂蜜酒\n我都不会把我的流星锤扔掉
Hey, hey, there's not enough mead in\nthe world to make me get rid of my flail.
既然我们拿不回押金了
Oh, hey, uh, Ted, since we're clearly\nnot getting our security deposit back,
我想你得把我的那一半钱赔我
I thought maybe you could\nreimburse me for my half.
等会 为啥我要比你赔偿的多?
Wait a second-- why should\nI have to pay more than you?
你对待这公寓就像John Bonham\n（著名摇滚鼓手 酗酒致死）\n对待他的中枢神经系统一样
Because you treated this apartment the way\nJohn Bonham treated his central nervous system.
扯淡
That's not true.
实例 A
Exhibit A.
这是什么?
What's that?
1986年的世界百科全书
A 1986 World Book encyclopaedia.
就是它伴着我长大
It's exactly the one I grew up with.
Encyclopaedia?(百科全书)
Encyclopaedia?
你认为该读作encyclo-pee-dia
Oh, you think it should be\npronounced encyclo-pee-dia.
这是个常见的错误
It's a common mistake.
但你要是在百科全书里找ae连音
But if you look at that squished together\n"ae" symbol in this here encyclopaedia,
你会知道这个连音是起源于\n英国撒克逊人...
you'll learn that it's a ligature\nderived from the Anglo-Saxon rune ash...
知道么 你得"配"钱了
You know, you're gonna\nhave to paedia for that.
你从没赔过钱
But you never did.
接着是实例 B
And then there's Exhibit B.
早上好 大家
Good morrow, fair gentles.
看我在文艺复兴节集会买到什么了
Look what I won at\nthe Renaissance Faire.
你同样也要负责在Robin是你女朋友时\n因她而起的损坏
And you're also responsible for any damage\nRobin did when she was your girlfriend.
什么损坏是因我而起的?
What damage did I cause?
还记不记得那天晚上你喝了\n不知道多少Molson啤酒 一副加拿大英雄模样?
Do you remember that night when you drank the\n12'er of Molson and you got all super Canadian?
史丹利杯 第六场
Stanley Cup, game six, eh?
纽约游骑兵队会后悔和法裔加拿大人打冰球的
The Rangers are about to be sorry they\never played shinny with the Canucks.
- 嘿 嘿 Robin\n- 恩?
- Hey, hey, Robin.\n- Yeah?
你要是能把球打过这个门我给你20块钱
I'll give you 20 bucks if you can\nshoot it through this front door.
你比Tim Horton的粉丝还狂热
Oh, you're nuttier than\na Tim Horton's maple log.
Timmy Ho!\nTimmy Ho!
够了 Robin 把球棍给我
That's it, Robin. Give me the stick.
小心我打的你满地找牙
I'll give you summer teeth.
这一堆 那一堆
Some are here, some are there.
Robin 给我球棍
Robin, give me the stick,
滚开 傻瓜
Take off, hoser.
够了!
That's it!
- 拉住她 快拉住她!\n- 让我扔掉? 我打死你还差不多!
- Get her, boys, get her!\n- Scrap? I'll scrap!
- 伙计们 得了吧!\n- 为了美国而战
- Guys, come on!\n- For America.
好了 都靠边 靠边站!
All right, break it, break it up!
Ted 不!
Ted, no!
你绝不该阻止姑娘打架! 绝不该!
You never break up a girl fight! Never!
那绝对是Barney的错
Entirely Barney's fault.
顺便说一下 壁炉上面有一大块烧焦痕迹
As, by the way, is the big\nscorch mark over the fireplace.
孩子们 为了能理解烧焦的故事
Kids, to understand the\nstory of the scorch mark,
我要先给你们讲Stewart的批斗会的故事
I first need to tell you the story of\nthe intervention for our friend Stewart.
怎么了?
What's going on?
Stewart 这是一次批斗会
Stewart, this is an intervention.
酒精改变了你 Stewart
The alcohol changes you, Stewart.
它让你变成了另一个人
It makes you a different person.
而我爱的是我当初嫁给的那位
And I'm in love with\nthe man that I married.
谢谢你
Thank you.
这真的是我所需要的压力
This is just the push I need.
我爱你们
I love you guys.
寿星老在这儿呢
There's the birthday boy.
到奔放的时候了 Stewie!
Time to let the party monster\nout of its cage, Stewie!
不!
No!
来吧 哥们
Come on, buddy.
大家可不想见Bruce Banner 伙计
People don't want to\nsee Bruce Banner, dude.
他们想看到Hulk\n(绿巨人变身前是Bruce Banner\n变身后是Hulk)
They want to see the Hulk.
Hulk Hulk Hulk...怎么回事?
Hulk, Hulk, Hulk... What?
这是我提纯维生素E用的东西
That's what I get for\nskimming the E-vite.
那天晚上 我们庆祝第一次成功的批斗会
TED: Later that day, we celebrated\nour first successful intervention.
我真为我们能帮助Stewart感到高兴
I am really proud of\nus for helping Stewart.
对啊 多么诚实 展现人性的时刻
Yeah, what an amazing\nhonest, human moment.
我赞同 耶!
I agree. Yay us.
Marshall 你真的还要戴那顶帽子?
Marshall, are you really\ngonna keep wearing that hat?
对啊 都两周了 Marshall
Yeah, it's been two weeks, Marshall.
很棒的两周...
Two awesome weeks...
绝对的 我要一直带着
and heck, yeah, I'm\ngonna keep wearing it.
Marshall 这是一次批斗会
Marshall, this is an intervention.
关于那帽子的
It's about the hat.
啊? 不...
Huh? No...
一切尽在我掌握中 不是吗?
I have it under control, okay?
我收放自如的
I can take it off whenever I want to.
亲爱的Marshall 我不喜欢那顶白痴帽子
Dear Marshall, I do not\nlike that stupid hat.
我想用球棍揍它
I want to beat it with a bat.
或是用叉子刺它
Or maybe stab it with a fork.
你带着它像是怪叔叔
It makes you look like such a dork.
在那之后 批斗会成了我们公寓定期活动
TED: After that, interventions became a\npretty regular thing around our apartment.
真该死
Cor blimey.
真他妈是个惊喜 这是关于什么的?
This is a nice bloody surprise.\nWhat's this about then?
Lily... 这是关于你那怪异的假英腔
Lily... it's about the\nweird fake English accent.
放屁
Oh, bollocks.
要说我喷的日晒色?
Spray tan?
他们用优惠券勾引你 然后你就上钩了
They reel you in with a coupon,\nand then you just get hooked.
哦 我们知道 亲爱的 我们知道
Oh, we know, sweetie, we know.
不 不 不 不 这可是新毛衣
No, no, no, no--\nthis is a new sweater.
怎么了?
What?
魔术把戏
The magic tricks.
特别是 有火的
Specifically, those involving fire.
魔术把戏?
Magic tricks?
伙计们 批斗会该是帮助他人
Guys, interventions are\nsupposed to help people,
不是去攻击你们不喜欢的一些小事
not attack every little thing\nyou don't like about them.
抱歉 真的让我生气
I'm sorry, but that really steams me.
让我火大!
That really burns me up!
我满腔炙热的怒火!
I mean, I am filled\nwith a white-hot rage!
谢谢
Thank you.
- 靠\n- 烧头发的味! 烧头发的味!
- Oh, shoot.\n- I smell hair! I smell hair!
到此烧焦痕迹的故事就讲完了
And that's the story of the scorch mark.
等等 很奇怪
Wait, that's weird.
我去壁橱的时候 我看到了批斗会的横幅
When I was going through the closet, I\nthought I saw the intervention banner.
那?
S-So?
横幅都烧毁了 为什么还有一个新的?
So, the banner burned up.\nWhy is there a new one?
里面有你们的信封 都写着"TED"
And there are sealed letters here\nfrom all of you that say "Ted."
你们给我也准备了一场批斗会?
Were you guys planning\nan intervention for me?
哦 那个 那个很白痴
Oh, that--\nthat was stupid.
对 忘了吧
Yeah, just, just forget about that.
因为什么? 鳄鱼?
Wh-What was it for? The Crocs?
- 洗发水?\n- 不是关于Stella 反正...
- The hair product?\n- Not Stella.
哦 天啊 是关于Stella的
Oh, my God, this was about Stella.
我刚说玩 "不是关于Stella"
I just said "Not Stella."
好像是关于你耳背的问题 Ted
So maybe it was about your\npoor listening skills, Ted.
- 什么?\n- 已经晚期了 看到没?
- What?\n- It's out of control. See?
你们认为我不该娶Stella
You guys don't think\nI should marry Stella.
Ted 我们赞成你 我们真的为你高兴
Ted, we do. We're all\nreally happy for you.
对 就像我说的 很白痴
Yeah. Like I said, it was stupid.
很显然 不是那样
Well, obviously, it wasn't,
因为我门已经在批斗"批斗会"上达成共识\n不再来愚蠢的批斗会了
because we agreed not to have any more stupid\ninterventions at our intervention intervention.
批斗会开得太多了
We're having too many interventions.
那么 你们对我和Stella有什么意见?
So, what was your big, serious\noblem with me and Stella?
耶! 耶! 都看见了吧!
Yes! Yes! In everyone's face!
你们都说"未来的Barney"那套不管用
You all said the "future\nBarney" thing wouldn't work.
你们说我疯了
You told me I was crazy.
我的心理医生说我疯了
My shrink told me I was crazy.
那现在谁又是有严重依附紊乱症的\n自恋狂呢 Grossbard医生?
Well, who's the narcissist with severe\nattachment disorder now, Dr. Grossbard?
批斗会横幅? 拿它干什么?
Intervention banner? What's that for?
Stella\nStella.
Ted 我不能这样无动于衷了...
Ted, I cannot stand idly by...
你一直把信带在身上?
You've just been carrying that around?
听我说完好吗 Ted?
Please, Ted?
"我不能眼睁睁看着你\n犯任何一个男人都会犯的错误――结婚"
"I cannot stand idly by while you make the biggest\nmistake any man can make-- getting married."
"记住我的话 \n这一切马上就灰飞烟灭了!"
"Mark my words,this whole\nthing is gonna go up in flames!"
哦 该死!\n火着的太早了
Oh, damn! I put the flame cue too early.
我还有很多更重要的事要说...
I had so many more important\nthings to say, and...
Ted 重点是 \n结婚是个很愚蠢的举动
The point is, Ted, marriage is stupid.
每年都有成千上万的\n20多岁的辣妹来酒吧
Every year, there are a million new\nhot 22-year-olds walking into bars,
并亲热地说 请我喝杯酒吧\n可我总觉得他们越来越没劲了
and call me "glass half full,"\nbut I think they're getting dumber.
得了吧 Barney 即使是你 到80岁\n也未必能钓上20多岁的美女了
Oh, come on, Barney, even you aren't still\ngonna be hitting on 22-year-olds when you're 80.
我接受挑战
I accept that challenge.
啥挑战?
What challenge?
证明我到80岁了还会像现在这样性感
To prove to you that I will be\nexactly this awesome when I'm 80,
我要装扮成老人\n勾引到一个22岁的辣妹
I will hook up with a 22-year-old\nwhile in my old-man makeup.
我一点也没那个意思
I didn't remotely challenge you to that.
其实我很想知道会发生啥
I mean, I definitely want to see it.
但我还是一点也没那个意思
But I didn't remotely\nchallenge you to that.
我想看看你们的信
I want to hear the other letters.
Ted 太荒谬了
Ted, this is ridiculous.
我...我们改变想法了
W-We changed our minds.
如果你又改回来了呢?
And suppose you change them back?
Lily 你先读吧
Lily, come on, let's hear yours.
自从...Gilbert的阅读水平与日俱增
Gilbert's reading skills have\nimproved drastically since...
等等 这封信本应该寄到\n幼儿园一个小朋友家的
Wait, this is a letter I meant to send\nhome with one of my kindergarteners.
Gilbert 你和一个叫Stella的女孩\n进展是不是太快了?
Gilbert, are things moving too fast\nbetween you and a girl named Stella?
但愿吧
I wish.
Robin 你的呢?
Robin, could I hear yours?
"亲爱的Ted \n不要把 说成
"Dear Ted, it's 'encyclo-pee-dia,'not\n'encyclo-pay-dia.'
你为啥总是以一种\n自命不凡的口气的说话"
Why do you always say things" "in\nthe most pretentious way possible?
听上去很无知 \n是"无知" 不是"无机"
It makes you sound douchey--" and\nthat's 'douchey,' not 'douch-ay.'"
这是你在我的语音批斗会上读的信
Yeah, you already read that one\nat my pronunciation intervention.
关于Stella的信呢?
Where's the letter about Stella?
我可没写\n我 我是你的前女友呢
I didn't write one--\nI-I'm your ex-girlfriend;
如果我在这问题上发表意见\n都很没有说服力
I figured anything I said on\nthe subject would sound catty.
还有 我比她辣多了\n谁在乎啊?
Plus, I'm hotter than her, so who cares?
Marshall?\nMarshall?
- 伙计 都已经过去的事情了 就不能...\n- 快读吧
- Dude, it's water under the bridge...\n- Please.
"亲爱的Ted \nStella的确是个很好的人
"Dear Ted, Stella seems\nlike a wonderful person.
但结婚是不是太快了点"
But you don't know her\nwell enough to get married.
"你还没有了解她到和她\n一起抚养一个7岁孩子的地步"
"You certainlydon't know her well enough to\ncommit to raising a seven-year-old with her."
这样鲁莽对你 对她 \n对她的孩子都没有任何好处
You're not ""doing her, her child" "or\nyourself any favors by rushing into this.
再等等吧
Just give it some more time."
伙计 这都是几个月前写的好吧?
Dude, that was months ago, all right?
我们现在已经了解她了 \n她很棒 而且你们很般配
That was before we got to know Stella and see how\nawesome she is and what a great couple you guys are.
所以我们决定不批斗你了
That's why we decided not to\neven have that intervention.
谢谢
Thank you.
我太需要你们支持我了
Because I-I really need you\nguys to be on board with this.
我们支持你
And we are.
希望你别生气
And we hope you're not mad at us.
当然不会
Course not.
你们又没说胡话
I mean, it's not like\nwhat you said was crazy.
你...你们的顾虑都是有据可依
Y-You had a lot of valid concerns.
是啊 但这些顾虑都消除了
Yeah, but concerns we have\ncompletely moved on from.
但你们说的对
But you had a point.
确实太快了点
I mean, this whole thing\nhas moved pretty fast.
也许是因为 时机已经成熟了
Well, you know what? Maybe that's\nbecause, uh, when it's right, yojust know.
是啊 但...但我们仍然\n需要彼此了解对方
Yeah, I guess, but-but we are still,\nyou know, getting to know each other.
Lily 也许你说对了
And, Lily, maybe you're right.
也许Stella会讨厌我的东西
Maybe Stella won't like any of my stuff.
比如这个机器人饼干罐
Like the robot cookie jar.
好像是我们为这里\n买的第一个东西 还记得吗?
This was, like, the first thing\nwe bought for this place, remember?
当然记得
Of course I do.
Marshall 我探测到\n胡桃饼干已经少的可怜了
Marshall, my sensors indicate that your\npecan sandy levels are dangerously low.
007系列珍藏版 记得不?
My collection of James\nBond movies. Remember?
我们一起按顺序看了 然后接下来的一个月 \nLily一嘴的英式怪腔调
We watched them all in order, and then Lily spoke in\nthat weird English accent for, like, the next month?
- 那很时髦\n- 才怪
- It was sophisticated.\n- No.
签了名的Bernie Kosar防滑鞋
My signed Bernie Kosar cleats.
大象灯
My elephant lamp.
英式电话亭
The English phone booth.
墨西哥阔边帽!
My sombrero!
Ted 你在干啥?
Ted, what are you doing?
拆包
Unpacking.
我决不离开这里!
I am never leaving this apartment!
别 别 Ted 别开箱\n你只是吓坏了
No, no, Ted, stop unpacking.\nYou're just freaking out.
我还没准备好\n承担那些责任
I'm not ready for all\nthe responsibility.
而 而且我的确没准备好\n做一个7岁孩子的继父
And-And I'm certainly not ready to\nbe a step-dad to a seven-year-old.
如果我结婚 \n然后搬去郊区
I mean, if I get married and move to\nthe suburbs, in the blink of an eye,
转眼间 我就老了!
I've become an old man!
好啊 漂亮小姐
Why, hello, young lady.
想吃奶糖吗?
You want a butterscotch candy?
你说"没共同语言"是啥意思?
What do you mean, "nothing in common"?
我们都年纪不小了啊
We're both seniors.
- 你太可爱了 多大了?\n- 83了
You're cute. How old are you?
- 你呢?
- 31\nThirty-one.
他彻底崩溃了
Okay, Ted has officially snapped.
10小时后搬家工就要来了
There are moving men\ncoming in ten hours.
他未婚妻还在New Jersey等他
His fianc\e is waiting\nfor him in New Jersey.
我们必须行动起来
We have to do something.
我来吧
I got this.
嘿 兄弟?
Hey, bud?
- 过来下\n- 啥事?
- Why don't you come here for a minute.\n- What?
听着 这一切都很正常
Look, I want you to know\nthis is all totally normal.
重大转变是挺吓人的\n害怕 退缩
Big transitions can be\nscary, and cold feet--
很快就会过去了 所以...
well, they're just\npart of the deal. So...
把小刀给我吧?
how about you give me the knife?
快给我啊
Give me the knife. Come on.
这样我也可以开箱卸行李了
So I can start unpacking, too.
我永远支持你 兄弟!
I'm staying here right by\nyour side forever, buddy!
- 耶!
- Marshall!\n- Yeah!\n- Marshall!
Lily  我们在这过得很好
Lily, our lives have been good here.
所以我们才一直拖延时间没打包
That's why we've been\nputting off packing.
因为潜意识里 \n我们都知道离开这里很愚蠢
Because subconsciously, we both know\nthat it would be stupid to leave.
这里很温暖 又有安全感
It's safe and warm here.
楼下有个酒吧 \n厨房里还有个饼干机器人呢
There's a bar downstairs, and\na cookie robot in the kitchen.
这是我的家 我也不走了!
This is my home, and I'm never leaving!
听你都说了些啥!
Listen to you!
你就像露营时软弱的胖孩子
You sound like that\nfat, dweeby kid at camp.
"爸 妈 我想回家了\n坏孩子抢我的呼吸机玩"
"Mom, Dad, I want to come home. The cool\nkids are playing keep-away with my inhaler."
真难以置信我老爸\n竟然我婚礼上读了那封信
I can't believe my dad read\nthat letter at our wedding.
Marshall 你不能对Lily这样
Marshall, you can't do this to Lily.
我知道你的新家有些问题
Yes, I know your new place\nhas had some problems,
地板是斜的 \n附近还有个污水处理厂
with the slanted floors and the\nnearby sewage treatment plant,
但是你们会把那变成自己的家的
but you're gonna turn\nit into a great home.
跟他说啊 Lily
Tell him, Lily.
那是个使所有梦想破灭的黑洞
It's a black hole\nwhere dreams go to die.
我也不搬了
I'm not moving, either.
- 哦 得了吧!\n- 太棒了!
- Oh, come on!\n- Yes!
你们快开箱
Okay, you guys finish unpacking.
我去做些饼干\n填饱我们的小机器人
I'm gonna go bake some\ncookies to fill R2-Sweet Tooth.
天啊 看看你们这群胆小鬼!
Oh, my God, look at you cowards!
这么怕改变
So afraid of any kind of change.
这么恐惧新事物
So terrified of anything new.
如...如此绝望地\n要留在舒适熟悉的地方
So-so desperate to cling to\nanything comfortable and familiar.
我不去日本了
I can't move to Japan.
太好了!
Yes!
我都是咋想? \n那也太远了吧
What was I thinking? It's so far away.
我也不会说日语
And I don't speak the language.
我连一张你们好看的照片都没有
I didn't even have any\ngood pictures of you guys.
哦 宝贝
Oh, sweetie.
人人都说改变是好事 对吧?
Everybody says change\nis so great, right?
可到底好些啥啊?
But what's so great about change?
嘿 谁想去楼下那个老地方?
Hey, who wants to walk\ndown to our same old bar,
坐在我们的老座位上\n点些老菜?
sit in our regular booth\nand order the usual?
- 好啊! 老规矩!\n- 我的最爱!
- Yeah! The usual!\n- My favorite!
哦 我的天啊!
Oh, my God.
呦 呦 呦
Well, well, well.
看来有人欠我200美元啊
I believe someone owes me $200.
Barney 没说打赌啊\n没人...
Barney, this was\nnever a bet-- nobody...
证明我80岁时\n还像现在一样性感
This proves that I will be\nthis awesome when I'm 80.
看我关节炎了还这么酷
Arthritis five.
- 我决定去New Jersey了\n- 啥?
- I'm moving to New Jersey.\n- What?
你和Marshall也应该搬走\nRobin还是应该去日本
And you and Marshall should move to your\nnew place, and Robin should go to Japan.
为啥啊?
Why?
因为不管我们愿不愿意\n我们还是会变老的
Because we're gonna get older\nwhether we like it or not,
问题是我们是去面对我们的生活
so the only question is whether\nwe want to get on with our lives
还是绝望地依附着过去\n像他那样了却一生
or desperately cling to the\npast and end up like that.
你说很爽的过一生吗?
You mean awesome?
伙计 我现在80了\n还能和一个辣妹亲热呢
I'm 80, dude, and I'm making\nout with a 22-year-old.
带我去你家吧 帅哥
Take me to your place, cheri.
我想看看你二战时的勋章
I want to see your World War II medals.
马上就来 小美人
In a minute, mon petite.
好吧 这不算数
All right, so that doesn't count.
啥? 为啥?
What? Why?
她是个法国人 \n这就像放倒球网打网球一样
She's French-- that's like\nplaying tennis with the net down.
知道吗?
You know what?
我来付房子押金
I'll cover the security deposit.
我很乐意 因为...
I'm glad to, because...
那个家里的每一个凹痕\n都是我将永远珍藏的回忆
every dent in that place represents\na memory that I'll cherish forever.
就一个条件\n我们现在起每周都为明年存10块钱
But on one condition: we all put aside\nten bucks every week for the next year,
然后我们来这\n点那瓶50年的苏格兰威士忌
and we come back here and we\nbuy that 50-year-old scotch,
为我们这个不可思议的\n人生大逆转之年干杯
and we toast the incredible\nlife-changing year we've all had.
从我们的座位上滚开
Get out of our booth.
我和我新组的家庭 \n住进新公寓里的Marshall和Lily
Me with my new family, Marshall\nand Lily in their new apartment,
还有太平洋沿岸\n最棒的美裔记者Robin
and Robin as the number one English-speaking\njournalist in the Pacific Rim,
来纽约相聚庆祝这一天
visiting us here in New\nYork to celebrate this day--
我们告别过去 \n迎接明天的一天
the day we closed an incredible chapter\nin our lives, only to open up a new one.
- 呃 我把手机丢在...\n- 滚
- Um, I think I left my cell...\n- Get out of here.
一年后 我们做到了
And one year later,\nthat's exactly what we did.
举起这2500块的苏格兰威士忌\n为这精彩的一年干杯吧
And so let's raise a glass of\n$2,500 scotch to one hell of a year.
- 不可思议\n- 难以置信啊
- Amazing.\n- That's unbelievable.
有点烟熏味\n还有陈年雪松和...的味道
It's kind of smoky, with\na hint of aged cedar and...
你们觉得和10块钱的威士忌有区别吗?
Do you guys taste the\ndifference and ten-dollar scotch?
- 一点也没\n- 没有
- Not at all.\n- No difference.
我还是喝红牛吧
I want to cut mine with Red Bull.
Wendy 能给我们拍张照吗?
Oh, Wendy, can you take a picture?
很多事情在那年都改变了\n但有些事永远不变
A lot of things did change that\nyear, but some things stayed the same.
我们去楼上继续狂欢怎么样?
So, uh, what do you say we move\nthis party upstairs to the apartment?
- 好\n- 好主意
- Yeah.\n- Great idea.
搞啥...
What the...
Barney 我们要批斗你了
Barney, this is an intervention.
不好意思 听不见
I'm sorry, I can't hear you.
别再扮"老鬼"了
Enough with the "old man" bit.
什么 老沙坑?
What about the old sand pit?
算了吧
Let it go.
下雪吧?
Let It Snow?
我爱死那段小曲了!
I love that old ditty!
我拿流星锤去
I'm getting my flail.
你要启航了?
You're setting sail?